inl.gov 2006-10-04

# The Idaho National Laboratory - Security/Privacy Statement

Thank you for visiting Idaho National Laboratory’s (INL) web site. We respect the need to protect your privacy. We collect no personal information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to provide that information to us under specific instances, such as in an e-mail. 

What you should know about visiting our web site: 

### Information we collect and store automatically

The INL collects and stores the following information automatically: 

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address of the domain from which you access the Internet (e.g., 123.456.789.012), whether yours individually or provided as a proxy by your Internet Service Provider (ISP).
  * Date and time you accessed our site.
  * Pages you visit.
  * Internet address of the web site from which you came to our site.
  * The browser name and version you are using.

We use summary statistics to help us make our site more useful, such as assessing what information is of most and least interest to visitors, and for other purposes such as determining the site's technical design specifications and identifying system performance or problem areas. 

Parts of our site use cookies to improve your experience. A cookie contains information that is either stored in your computer’s memory, or in a file on your computer’s hard disk. Cookies that are stored in your computer’s memory are automatically removed when you quit your browser. Cookies that are stored in a file on your computer’s hard disk will have an expiration date after which time they will no longer be valid. It is our policy to notify you and obtain your approval before a cookie is stored on your computer, to explain what the cookie collects, and how the information is used. If you encounter a cookie that does not terminate upon ending a session at an inel.gov web site — without your approving of it’s use and there is no explanation or the explanation is not clear or reasonable — please let us know. 

For additional information about cookie usage on Federal web sites, please visit the following: 

  * [Department of Energy's computer Incident Advisory Capability (CIAC) Bulletin I-034: Internet Cookies](http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/i-034.shtml)
  * [OMB Memorandum 99-18 "Privacy Policies on Federal Web Sites dated June 2, 1999](http://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/memoranda/m99-18attach.html)

### Sending us personal or confidential information

If you choose to provide us with personal information - by sending us an e-mail or by filling out an online form with your personal information and submitting it to us through our web site - please be aware that we may use that information to 

  * Respond to your message
  * Help gather the requested information.

We do not create individual profiles with the information you provide. We do not collect information for commercial marketing. However, the material you submit may be seen by various people and collected, such as: 

  * We may enter the information you send into our electronic database.
  * Share it with our attorneys and/or INL staff.
  * We may also share it with other government agencies and parties who have an interest in the activities and mission of the INL.

Online forms submitted from the https://secure.inl.gov/ domain utilize Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for encryption of transmitted data. E-mail and online forms which are not part of the https://secure.inl.gov/ domain are not secure against interception and senders cannot expect privacy. While we believe the secure method is the preferred method to send business sensitive material or personal information electronically, we cannot guarantee the security of any electronic data transmissions. If your communication will be through a non-secured method and will include business sensitive material or personal information like your bank account, charge card, or social security number, please send it by postal mail instead to the following address: 

INL  
P.O. Box 1625  
Idaho Falls, ID 83415 

To send proprietary information to the INL that must be treated confidentially, please contact the Technology Transfer and Commercialization Office at (208) 526-4299. 

### Security notice

This web site is part of a Federal computer system used to accomplish Federal functions. The Department of Energy monitors this web site for security purposes to ensure it remains available to all users and to protect information in the system. By accessing this web site, you are expressly consenting to these monitoring activities. 

Unauthorized attempts to defeat or circumvent security features, to use the systems for other than intended purposes, to deny service to authorized users, to access, obtain, alter, damage, or destroy information, or otherwise to interfere with the system or its operation are prohibited. Evidence of such acts may be disclosed to law enforcement authorities and result in criminal prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 (Pub. L. 99-474) and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996 (Pub. L. 104-294), (18 U.S.C. 1030), or other applicable criminal laws. 

### General disclaimer

WITH RESPECT TO INFORMATION FROM THIS SERVER, NEITHER THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT NOR BATTELLE ENERGY ALLIANCE (BEA) NOR ANY OF THEIR EMPLOYEES, MAKES ANY WARRANTY, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR ASSUMES ANY LEGAL LIABILITY OR RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, OR USEFULNESS OF ANY SUCH INFORMATION, OR OF ANY APPARATUS, PRODUCT, OR PROCESS DISCLOSED, OR REPRESENTS THAT ITS USE WOULD NOT INFRINGE PRIVATELY OWNED RIGHTS. Reference to any specific commercial product, process, or service by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise does not necessarily constitute or imply its endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the United States Government or BEA. The views and opinions of authors expressed on this web site do not necessarily state or reflect those of the United States Government or any agency and shall not be used for advertising or product endorsement purposes. 

### Links to other sites

This web site has links to many other Federal agencies. In a few cases we link to private organizations. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. 

### Feedback

We welcome your feedback at any time. 
  *[INL]: Idaho National Laboratory
  *[BEA]: Battelle Energy Alliance
